While taking health insurance, its
increasing prices are definitely a bummer.
Many times you have to pay a lot of money
for a health insurance policy.  So today's
video is dedicated to affordable health
insurance.  What are the plans that
you will get under Rs 15,000 with decent
cover?  We will talk about these plans in detail.
What are the similarities in these plans
?  What are the features?  What are you
getting?  What's in it for you?  In the end, we will
talk about what is premium?   For the
individual as well as for the family.  So stay
till the end of the video.  This is going to be a very
useful video.
[Music]
A quick reminder before we start the video,
if you haven't already, please subscribe to our channel
so
you can keep getting such useful videos.  Let's move on to the
video.  Here we are
comparing five plans whose
premium is under ₹15,000 per annum.  The first is the
Neevapa Aspire Diamond Plus variant.   The
second is ICICI LB Elevate Base Plan.
Third is Aditya Birla Active One Max
Plan.  Fourth is ManipalCigna Saravaha
Plan and Fifth is Care Supreme Plan.
So let us understand these plans in detail
and also see
what the premiums are in the end because we are
talking about affordable insurance.
I would like to share with you the ICR of these companies
which is Incurred Claim Ratio of Nivapa is
59.02%,
of ICICI LB is 78.85%, of Aditya Birla is
68.31%,
of Manipal Cigna is 63.78%, of
Care Health is 57.69%,
so first we will compare all of them on the
criteria of room rent eligibility.  So,
talking about room rent eligibility, room
rent eligibility basically means which
room you are eligible for when you are
taking these health insurance policies.  So, there are
no room rent restrictions in the Neema Aspire Diamond Plus variant and up to the
sum assured is covered.
Single private AC room is available in ICIC Low LMA Elevate Base plan.
If you wish to upgrade your room, a
Room Type Modification Rider
is available to upgrade your room
or bring it on a twin sharing basis.  There
is no capping in Aditya Birla Activ 1 Max.  You can choose any room.
Room modification rider available.
If you want to downgrade the room, the
cost will be reduced.
We are comparing the best plans of Manipal Cigna Sarvaha
here.  Single Private AC Room
is covered.  ICU is covered up to some
assured.  Talking about Care Health's Supreme Plan, there is
no room run capping as you can
claim up to the sum assured.  Minimum and
maximum entry age.  The
minimum entry age for Neevapa Aspire is 18 and the maximum is 65.
Minimum entry age for child is 91 days.
Children can stay in this plan for a maximum of 30 years.  The
minimum entry age for ICICI Low LBA Elevate is 18 for an adult and the
maximum is 125 years.  So you can understand
that there is no maximum entry age.  When we are
saying 125, then there would be a very rare chance
that someone would be 125 years old.  So there
is no restriction on maximum entry age.
Children between 91 days to 30 years of age
can continue the policy as dependents.
Aditya Birla Active One Max has
no age limit from 18 years onwards.   The maximum is 18 and the
minimum is 18 in Manipal Cigna Sarvaha Uttam plan also.  There
is no maximum limit.  The policy can be continued for children from 91 days to 30
years.  The
minimum entry age for Care Supreme plan is
18 years.  There
is no maximum entry age and
dependent children can be added to the policy from 91 days to 24 years.
All these
policies come with your life long renewability
clause.  Meaning this is the entry
age that one can enter maximum up to this age.
But those who can renew, you can
renew the policy life long.   There
is no restriction.  Until and
unless any fraudulent activity
is proven or your policy is terminated, then
that is a different matter.  But otherwise you
can renew the policy for life long.
Minimum sum assured in Nimapa Aspire is Rs 3 lakh and
maximum is Rs 1 crore. In ICIC LBD Base Elevate
Plan, minimum sum assured is Rs 5 lakh and maximum is Rs 6 crore.
Option of unlimited sum assured is also available. In Aditya Bill Active One
Max, your minimum sum assured is Rs 5 lakh and maximum is Rs
6 crore. In Manipal Cigna Sarfa
Uttam, minimum sum
assured is Rs 5 lakh and maximum sum assured up to Rs 3 crore is available.
In Care Supreme, sum assured from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 1 crore
is available. If we talk about policy tenure, then
one year, two year and three year
policies are available. In Nimapa Aspire, you
know that if you take a multi-tenure
policy, you get a discount.  This
means that if you
pay the premium for 2-3 years together upfront, you will
get a discount on the premium.
Five years option is now also available in ICICI LB Elevate Base Plan.
1 2 3 4 5
All five options are available.  You can choose
and discount will vary accordingly.
Among other policies, tenures of one, two and three years are available in Aditya Birla
Active One Max Manipal, Cigna Sarvaha
Uttam and Care Supreme plans.
If we talk about bonus, your bonus can be
in different forms.  One could be a no claim
bonus, that is, you did not make a claim,
hence the company is giving you the bonus.  One
could be your cumulative bonus which is
loyalty addition that every year the company
is giving you a cumulative bonus because you are
loyal to them and renewing the
policy.  And thirdly, if you do not take the claim,
you can get a booster that if you do
not take the claim, we will carry forward your sum assured.
So Nima Bupa Aspire
Diamond Plus plan has Booster Plus
benefit.  Meaning, whatever you do not use will get carried
forward to the next year, the
uncentralized sum assured will be carried forward
and in this, carry forward is done according to the age,
according to the entry age.
If you are entering the policy at the age of 18 to 35,
then the maximum sum assured will
go up to five times.  Suppose there
is a policy of Rs 10 lakh.  If you don't use it then next
year you will get 20, 30, 40 and 50.  If you fall in the 18 to 35 age
group.  If your entry
age is 36 to 45 then maximum it will
go up to three times.  If your entry age is 46
plus then it will go up to two times.  Talking about ICC LB, the
no claim bonus here is 20%.
20% will be given every year.  This is
irrespective of the claim.  This
is a guaranteed cumulative bonus.  The maximum will go up to 100%.  There is
one more benefit in ICICI LBA which is called
power booster.  That is an add-on, an
optional rider.  If you take that, then
you will get 100% bonus on top of this bonus every year
up to infinity.  There
is no maximum limit.  Aditya Birla Activ Max will
give you 100% bonus every year up to a maximum of 500%.  So
your policy will be five times in the next five
years and this is also irrespective of the
claim.  And if any other claim comes, it will
not be deducted.  Manipal Signals
Sarvaah Uttam has a piggy bank benefit in
which the sum assured increases by 100% every year
and the maximum is 1000%, which means
your cover will increase 10 times in these 10 years.  And this
is also irrespective of the claim.  In Care Health
Supreme, you are given 50% bonus
next year and maximum 100% and if
future claims come then it will not be reduced.
You can also add NCB Super in this,
which is again an add-on
optional rider.  Where your return will increase by 100% every year
up to a maximum of 500%.  So whatever you are getting
guaranteed 50 and 100, you are getting it.  You will get
500% more on top of that.
If you pay additional premium for NCB Super.
Day care
hospitalization.  Day care hospitalization is a type of
hospitalization where
you do not need to stay in the hospital for 24 hours.
You get discharged before that.
So day care hospitalization
is covered in all these plans.  AYUSH
Hospitalization: AYUSH Ayurveda, Yoga, Unani,
Siddha, Homeopathy, its hospitalization
is also covered in all these policies.  Then
domiciliary hospitalization.  Domiciliary
hospitalization is hospitalization at
home.  It happens due to two conditions.  Firstly,
beds are not available in the hospital.  Like
Covid like situation.  If the second patient
is so critical that he cannot be taken to the hospital, then he can be
treated at home.
Hospitalization may occur.  Which is
called domiciliary hospitalization.  That too
is covered in all your five plants up to
some assured.  Now let's talk about emergency
road ambulance.  So the expense of going to the hospital
by road ambulance which is
emergency road ambulance.  Nima
Bupa Aspire covers up to sum
assured.  ICICI Low LBA Elevate plan
also covers Age Per Actuals up to Sum
Assured.  Aditya Birla Active One Max
is covered under Age Per Actuals up to sum
assured.  In ManipalCigna Sir Uttam also
up to sum assured is covered as per
actuals. In Care Health Supreme Plan,
if your sum assured is below ₹1 lakh then
₹10,000 and if it is above ₹15 lakh then up
to sum assured as per actuals will be paid.
Now let's talk about emergency air
ambulance which is useful for domestic evacuation.
So this is a domestic air ambulance for
emergency cases.  Neevapa
Aspire Diamond Plus plan covers
up to sum assured.  You can add ICICI Low LBA through rider.
This is not an inbuilt feature.
You can also add riders to the Aditya Birla Active One.  This
is not an inbuilt feature of the policy.
You can also add riders through Manipal Signa Sarvaha Uttam.
Maximum cover is ₹1
lakh.  Can add through rider in Hale Supreme.
The maximum is ₹5 lakh.  Now let's talk about
refill benefit or restore
benefit or reset benefit.
What is this basically?  What happens is that if
your base sum assured, whatever you have
taken from LETS, plus any
bonuses, gets exhausted
in a particular year, then a refill will be triggered in your policy.  The
refill is triggered after the first claim.  So suppose you have a
policy of Rs 10 lakh and it gets exhausted and there is a
need to claim again
in the same year, then you will be refilled Rs 1 lakh again
for any person any claim,
meaning you can take it for the same claim or for
different claims.  Same
person can take it or different person can also
claim it.  But it has to be a
different hospitalization.  That will be the
trigger for the next hospitalization.  So the
Niwapa Aspire plan has your Reashore
Plus.  This means that once your refill is
triggered, it will remain recharged forever in the first year.
Your refill will always be included
with your policy.  If you want to understand it in more detail, then
detailed video of Neevapa Aspire
is available.  In that I have
explained it in great detail.  Then we will
talk about ICICI LB Elevate Plan.
In that also you have unlimited number of times
for any illness.
Unlimited number of times for
any illness in Aditya Birla Active One Max.  Manipal Cigna Saravaha Uttam
Plan offers 100% of sum assured multiple
times.  Unrelated
means unlimited number of times for both the illnesses.
Health Supreme also has unlimited restore
for any illness.  Annual wellness test.  So
annual health checkup is a feature of some policies.
In some policies you have to add this as an add-on.
So
this is inbuilt in the Neevapa Aspire plan.  You can claim from Day One
and it is on a cashless basis.
Meaning, if you have taken the policy and
you want to get the test done even after a week or a month from the date,
you can do it.  This is on a
cashless basis.  How much you will get depends on your sum assured.
You will have to book through their health application.   The
maximum limit is up to Rs 10,000.  ICICI
LBAT base plan also offers cashless basis pay
and you can book through IL Tech Care app.
This is listed on S.  Aditya
Birla Active and Max
are also listed on Once a Year offer and
are on cashless basis.  Manipal Sina Saravaha is inbuilt in your plan.  It's
Once a Year.  And in Care Health
Supreme also, Once a Year for All Insured
and this is given to you once every year.
Pre and Post Hospitalization
Expenses: These are the expenses that occur
before and after going to the hospital.
Related to the same illness.
Suppose you have a fever.  You
saw a doctor.  Took some medicines, got diagnostic
tests done, had doctor consultation,
pharmacy bills came.  After that, he did not get cured
or some diagnosis was made on the basis of which the
doctor admitted him.  So all the
expenses that you had earlier were for 60 days and
also after hospitalization, you have
prescriptions and medicines.
Suppose someone is on physiotherapy, has met with an
accident and is discharged after that.
So all those expenses will be
covered for 180 days.  So
in Neema Aspire, expenses are 60 days before and 180 days after.
Expenses before 90 days and after 180 days in ICICI LBD Elevate.
You can claim expenses for 90 days before and 180 days after the Aditya Birla Activ Max.
In Manipal Singhana Saravaha Uttam Plan also, expenses of 90 days before and 180 days
after can be claimed.
In the Careel Supreme plan, you can get reimbursed the expenses for 60 days before and
180 days after.
Now let's talk about wellness
benefits.  There are some benefits
which cover your illness.  You
know that any hospitalization is covered under health insurance policy.
But focus is also on wellness
so that you can take care of your health.
So Neevapa Aspire has Live Healthy
benefit.  This means that based on the number of steps you walk,
you will be given a
discount at the time of
renewal which is up to 30% which is
called Live Healthy Benefit.  And they track this
through your application.  So,
download the app of Neevapa Health or any policy which has wellness benefits.  The number of steps you walk and
your fitness activity will be
tracked and on that basis you will be given a discount on renewal.
So in Neevapa there is
30% IC long and in Deliveroo up to 20%
discount is available.  Aditya Bill
Active One Max has health returns
that are up to 100%.  Yes, up to 100%.
If you are very fit.  If you take great
care of your health then you
get 100% discount.  This means that you only have to
pay GST and all the remaining
premiums are discounted at
renewal.  Manipal Cigna has up to 20%
and this is the Wealthy app of Manipal Cigna which
you have to download.  Care Health Supreme offers
wellness benefits up to 30% off on end
wellness along with some value added
services.  Like you will
get discount on diagnostic tests.
You will get a discount on the pharmacy.  Free
home delivery will be available and so on.
You can avail all these things when you
download their health application.  E-
consultation means you
can do teleconsultation with the doctor.
You can consult doctors in their network an unlimited number of times.
Like in Niva Bupa
Aspire you have unlimited teleconsultation.
Booking has to be done through the application.
Unlimited teleconsultation is also provided in the ICICI LB base plan.
And Aditya
Birla Activ Max has this rider which you
can add so that you can consult doctors unlimited number of
times.
And these doctors are from their panel only.  So
you will have to book the appointment from the application itself,
from the health application.  Manipal Cigna
Sarvaha Uttam plan also offers unlimited e-consultation
and Care Health Supreme also offers unlimited e-
consultation.  Modern
Treatments and Robotic Surgeries.  So
modern treatments and robotic surgeries
are covered up to the point in all these five plans.
There is no submit.  All modern
treatments, all robotic surgeries which
are specified by IRDA
are covered.  Non-Payable Items.  So there are many
items which are consumable items
which are not covered in your policy
, are not inbuilt.  For that,
riders have to be hired.  For example,
Safeguard and Safeguard
Plus riders are available in Nima Bupa Aspire.  There is Safeguard
which has 68 items.  There is Safeguard Plus
which has a list of 147 non-payable items.
So the whole thing is covered.
Your non-payable items will be
covered according to the rider you opt for.  Second is ICICI LB Base
Plan, here you will add Pay Claim Protector
which will cover your non-payable items.
Then your Aditya Bill Active One
Max is inbuilt in it.  Your non-payable
items are covered.  There is a list of 147 items.
ManipalCigna Sarvaha Uttam Plan has
NME DME Rider which is Non Medical
Expenses and Durable Medical Expenses
Rider which you can add to cover
your non payable items.  The Care Health Supreme
plan also offers you a Claim Shield Rider to
cover non-payable items.
OPD cover.  So OPD is done on optional basis.
You can add OPD Well Consult Rider in Neevapa Aspire.
So that you
can also do OPD consultations up to
₹2000.  ICIC LBA Elevate has Be Fit rider
which you can add for OPD
consultation.
OPD rider is not available in Aditya Birla Activ Max at present but
you will find an OPD rider in future.
Manipal Cigna Sarvaha Uttam also does
not have OPD rider with this plan.  May come in the future.  Care
Health Supreme has a Care OPD rider which
you can add if OPD
is required by you.  So copayment.  So
co-payment is where
you have to share some percentage at the
time of claims.  So there is no copayment in Neep Aspire.
You can make voluntary copayments in ICICI LBAD Elevate.  Meaning,
if you want your premium to be reduced,
you can make a co-payment.
Aditya Birla Active & Max also does
not have the option of co-payment.  You can add copayment as a rider
in the Uttam plan in Manipal Signal Saravaha plan.
This rider is not available even in Care Health.  Then
comes the deductible option.
Deductible option is one in which you
pay an initial amount at the time
of claims against which the insurance
company gives you a discount.
Suppose you say that
you will pay the first Rs 10,000-20,000 and if any claim comes, the
insurance company gives you a discount in return.
This happens on an optional basis.
So deductible
options are available in Neema Bhupa.  Deductible option is not available in ICC LB Base Plan.
Deductible has just been introduced in Aditya Birla One Activ Max.
You can choose
if you want to reduce the premium.
Deductible option is also available in Manipal Cigna Surfaya Uttam but daily
and annual aggregate deductible is also available.  Care
Health Supreme does not have a deductible option.
Now let's talk about maternity
expenses.  Your delivery and
newborn baby expenses at maternity are covered.  So as a
rider will be available.  Like
Niveapair has miracle benefits.  The Miracle
Benefit covers your delivery costs plus
newborn baby expenses.  There are
certain limits to it.  You should
check that if you
want to avail maternity benefits.  So
we have also made a video on maternity benefits in which we are
comparing maternity plus.  There
we have made the comparison by focusing more on maternity.
So you can refer that.
We will put its link below.  You can
also add on maternity and newborn baby coverage in ICIC LMB Elevate.
Maternity rider
is currently not available on Aditya Birla Activ Max.  This option is
not available in Manipal Cigna Sarvaha Uttam and
also in Care Health Supreme.
Global cover means if
you want to get treatment outside India,
borderless rider is available
in Neema Aspire.
Global cover is not currently available in any other plan.  So this
is also as a rider.  So now let's talk about
waiting periods.  So the initial waiting
period in these plans is 30 days
except your Manipal Cigna Sarva Uttam
plan which has zero waiting period.   There
is no waiting period there.
Similarly, the waiting period for slow growing illness is
two years in all.
Accept Manipal Cigna Sarvaah plan
as it has zero waiting period.
If you want to add that waiting period then
you can take wait.
Due to which the waiting period will be added.  Meaning,
we generally see that riders come in such a way
that the waiting period is reduced or it will
add to the waiting period if you
take the waiting rider, it is best
in all.  Now let us come to the
waiting period of pre-existing conditions.  The
waiting period for pre-existing conditions is
36 months in all the policies except
Manipal Signal Sarvaah Uttam.  Because there
is no waiting period here.  Now let's talk about
optional riders.  This is what is
inbuilt in the base plan.  Now
what are the optional riders that you
can add so that your policy can be further
enhanced.  Niva Aspire has a
cashback optional rider that gives you cashback
if you do not make a claim.
Borderless which stands for world wide coverage.
Future ready means you are guaranteeing
that your spouse will be added in the future.
Then fast forward means taking 2 year and 3
year policies together.  Where
you can claim coverage for 2 years and 3 years together.
Be it Base Sum Assured or
Maternity Miracles Sum Assured.  Then there is
Safeguard and Safeguard Plus for non-payable
items.  Then there is hospital cash.  This means that for the number of
days you remain admitted in the hospital
, you get a daily cash benefit of up to
₹4,000.  Personal Accidental is what covers your
accidental death and permanent disability.
We have disease management
rider which is called DM also.  It
covers your BP and sugar from day one.
Then there's the Tied Network Discount.  If you
want to go into the limited network,
you are given a 15% discount.
Detailed video is also available on tiered networks.
You Can Refer To
Understand More In Detail.  Then there is well
consult which is OPD rider.
About the riders of the ICIC Labard Elevate Plan.
Durable Medical Equipment Rider.   There
is a dependent accommodation benefit rider.
You can add annual health checkup.   There
is a claim protector for non-payable items.
Power Booster which increases your sum assured by 100%
every year.  Up to infinite
sum assured.  Infinite Care is where
you can claim infinite sum assured in one policy.
If you have taken this rider then you get
Domestic Air Ambulance cover
Network Advantage and you
get discount on Tiered Network Nursing at Home
Compassionate Visit Inflation Protector
Convalescence Benefit Critical Illness Rider
You can add
Personal Accident Rider for lumpsum payout Jump Start Room
Modifier so that you can modify the room
Copayment and Bfit Rider which is
OPD Rider Now let's talk
about the riders of Aditya Birla Active One Max.  The
first is the Chronic Care Rider.  If you
want to bring existing conditions which are A, B, C D, Asthma, BP, Cholesterol, Diabetes, Obesity, COPD, Heart Condition on Day 1 then you
can choose this rider.  Reducing the Room
Category.  If you want to reduce the room category, you can
take room modifier.
Deductible is an optional rider.  Air ambulance is
your optional rider.  Then tele consultation
and DME.  These are your optional riders.   There are
many riders available in Manipal Signa Sarvam.
This is the wait to
add waiting period surplus benefit.
Two X is covered in this.
Personal Accidental Cover
Again for Accidental Death and Disability if you add this from Day One.  There
is a rider for non-medical expenses and durable medical expenses.  Air
ambulance, room rent modification available.  There
is voluntary copayment.  There is a deductible rider
that you can choose.  Now let's talk
about the riders of Carel Supreme.
NCB Super is a bonus that includes up to 500% of your
sum assured.  PED Wait
Period Modification: If you want to reduce the PED wait period from 36 months, then
you can take this rider.  Annual Health Checkup
Annual Health Checkup rider is an instant
cover that allows you to cover conditions like hypertension, diabetes,
hyperlipidemia and asthma, A B C D,
from day one.
Claim Shield covering 68 illnesses
and Care OPD.  Now we started this video
about affordable plans.  Now let us
talk about premiums here.
How affordable are their premiums?
Here I have taken three sum assured.  You have
taken cover for 5 L, 7.5 L and 10 L.  And
here I am telling you the premium for individual as well as for
family.
So
you can see accordingly whichever is suitable for you.
So the premium I have taken here is for
zone two.  And the age of the individual
taken is 35.  It is the highest age.  And
if you look at the premium for individual, it is Rs 5 lakh.
₹1402 for Neevapa Aspire.  ICICI
lmb for Elevate is 7454.  Aditya Birla
Activ Max 8065
Manipal Cigna 8269 And then comes Care
Health Supreme 752 Now here
I have not added any riders that the premium is of zone two, it is at the
age of 35 and the premium is Rs 5 lakh.
GST 18% is included in this.
Now let's buy this for the family.  The
highest age is 35 and
we took a policy for two adults.  So the premium in Nivapa will be
10483 ICICI Aitya Birla 11552 Manipal
Cigna 13122 and Care Supreme 983. Similarly, the
premiums of 7.5 and 10 are also in front of you.
So an effort has been made to keep all premiums
below Rs 15,000.  So that
you can take this plan in the affordable category.
So this was what we wanted to convey from our side.
What affordable health insurance is available to you
and what you can avail.  You
can customize the plan according to your needs.  As you can
see, there are a lot of riders and a lot of
variants available.  We have picked those variants
whose premium is comparatively
lower.  So you can see according to yourself
what your need is?
What is your suitability?  You can choose the plan accordingly.  If you have
any questions, please share them
in the comment box.  If you
want to give any feedback, please let us know.  If you
want to reach out to our team to buy the
policies, you can also connect.
Our contact number email ID is given.   There
is also a link to a Google Form.  If you fill it,
our team will connect with you.
Quick reminder before we go, if you have
n't subscribed to our channel yet, do so.
So that you get the right information
at the right time.  See you in the next video.  Till then
stay safe.  Take care.  Bye-bye.
Om